<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Latest News &amp; Advice &#8211; LinkHS</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Helping teenagers find jobs since 2021</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 10:19:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Points To Consider Before Accepting A New Job Offer!</title>
		<link>./../../../points-to-consider-before-accepting-a-new-job-offer-2/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../points-to-consider-before-accepting-a-new-job-offer-2/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bimal Dhanu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 10:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Latest News & Advice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://demo.nokriwp.com/?p=119</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When you’re considering a job offer, there’s more to think about than just how much you are going to be [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you’re considering a job offer, there’s more to think about than just how much you are going to be paid. Salary is, of course, important, and it could be the deciding factor in accepting a job offer.</p>
<p>However, the other parts of a compensation package are almost as important. Your paycheck will cover your monthly bills, but you also need to consider employee benefits, perks and the non-tangible things that make a job a good one.</p>
<p>Here are some things to consider before accepting a job offer, including what to look for when evaluating job offers, and when it can make sense to turn one down</p>
<ul>
<li class="TrT0Xe">Evaluate the <b>Job Offer</b>.</li>
<li class="TrT0Xe">Evaluate Employee Benefits and Perks.</li>
<li class="TrT0Xe">Get a Good Retirement Plan.</li>
<li class="TrT0Xe">Evaluate Stock Options.</li>
<li class="TrT0Xe">Ask for More Time.</li>
<li class="TrT0Xe">Negotiate Salary.</li>
<li class="TrT0Xe">Negotiate a Counter <b>Offer</b>.</li>
<li class="TrT0Xe">When To Turn Down a <b>Job Offer</b>.</li>
</ul>
<h3><span class="content-list__text">Evaluate the Job Offer</span></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-medium wp-image-123 alignright" src="https://elementor.nokriwp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/woman-hand-desk-office-288x300.jpg" alt="" width="288" height="300" /></p>
<p>Before you say yes, you’ll take the job, consider the entire compensation package &#8211; salary, benefits, perks, work environment, the schedule and the hours.  Also, consider the job description and if you would be happy working at this job with this company.</p>
<p>Weigh the pros and cons and take some time to think about the offer. You don’t have to say yes right away if you are going to accept. Ask the employer when they need a response by. If you have two offers to consider, use a comparison list to help you decide which one to accept.</p>
<h3 class="content-list__title"><span class="content-list__text">Evaluate Employee Benefits and Perks</span></h3>
<p>Employee benefits, including health insurance, retirement plans, vacation and sick leave, and life and disability insurance can represent up to 30% of your compensation package. It&#8217;s important to take the time to review what you&#8217;re offered to make sure it&#8217;s what you and your family need at this stage of your working life.</p>
<h3 class="content-list__title"><span class="content-list__text">Get a Good Retirement Plan</span></h3>
<p>Not all retirement plans are created equal. A great retirement plan can significantly increase the value of a job offer, and may even trump higher salary at another employer. Review these guidelines for what constitutes a good retirement plan, so you can compare what you may have already with what you’re being offered.</p>
<h3 class="content-list__title"><span class="content-list__text">How to Accept or Decline a Job Offer</span></h3>
<p>Once you have made a decision on whether to accept or decline the offer, it&#8217;s time to let the employer know. Take the time to formally accept or turn down the position, and do it gracefully so you don&#8217;t burn any bridges with the prospective employer.</p>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=.%2Fpoints-to-consider-before-accepting-a-new-job-offer-2%2F&amp;linkname=Points%20To%20Consider%20Before%20Accepting%20A%20New%20Job%20Offer%21" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=.%2Fpoints-to-consider-before-accepting-a-new-job-offer-2%2F&amp;linkname=Points%20To%20Consider%20Before%20Accepting%20A%20New%20Job%20Offer%21" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_email" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/email?linkurl=.%2Fpoints-to-consider-before-accepting-a-new-job-offer-2%2F&amp;linkname=Points%20To%20Consider%20Before%20Accepting%20A%20New%20Job%20Offer%21" title="Email" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=.%2Fpoints-to-consider-before-accepting-a-new-job-offer-2%2F&#038;title=Points%20To%20Consider%20Before%20Accepting%20A%20New%20Job%20Offer%21" data-a2a-url="./../../../points-to-consider-before-accepting-a-new-job-offer-2/index.html" data-a2a-title="Points To Consider Before Accepting A New Job Offer!"></a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../points-to-consider-before-accepting-a-new-job-offer-2/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Career trends: The important skills you’ll need for Job</title>
		<link>./../../../career-trends-the-important-skills-youll-need-for-the-jobs-of-the-next-upcoming-years/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../career-trends-the-important-skills-youll-need-for-the-jobs-of-the-next-upcoming-years/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bimal Dhanu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 12:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Latest News & Advice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://demo.nokriwp.com/?p=24</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Demographics, cultural trends, and new technologies are rapidly changing the job market. People are living much longer than we used [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Demographics, cultural trends, and new technologies are rapidly changing the job market.</p>
<p>People are living much longer than we used to. New technologies and automation are rapidly replacing repetitive jobs. New communication tools are eliminating formerly popular mediums for disseminating information (good-bye printed newspapers) at the same time as requiring more advanced media literacy skills for most new jobs.</p>
<p>After researching job market shifts for a recent Thinkopolis labour report, we’ve taken a closer look at how to choose education and training for the job market of the next five to ten years.</p>
<p><strong>Key take-aways</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>When it comes to landing a job, digital literacy is the new literacy</li>
<li>Eight jobs that will always be in demand</li>
<li>Where the jobs will (and won’t) be created over the next five to ten years</li>
<li>Communications, tech savvy, and constant learning will be required for jobs in all fields</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Technology</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-74 size-medium alignright" src="https://elementor.nokriwp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/pexels-photo-273222-288x300.jpeg" alt="" width="288" height="300" /></p>
<p>On the bright side of jobs being replaced by technology is that this means a boost in technology-related career options. Every new form of automation or robotics requires engineers and technicians to develop and maintain.</p>
<p>The move from desktops and laptop to smart phones and tablets has created a current high demand for application developers and designers. So while we can’t predict exactly where technology will be at in 2020, but we can advise people to keep up with the latest trends and tools of their time.</p>
<p><strong>Healthcare</strong></p>
<p>The aging population will continue to require more workers in a wide range of medical professions. Doctors, obviously, will be in demand, but also Nurses, Healthcare Managers and Technicians, Pharmacists, Care-givers and Elder-care Coordinators.</p>
<p>A mixture of healthcare and technology education would be a powerful combination. Biomedical engineering is expected to be one of the hottest fields over the coming decade.</p>
<p>Alternately, learning both healthcare and business management skills could also lead to numerous career paths in hospitals, clinics, private care institutions and public health departments.</p>
<p><strong>Business and Finance</strong></p>
<p>Businesses will continue to seek new ways attract customers and understand market trends. Data analysts, and market researchers will continue to be hot career paths for the foreseeable future.</p>
<p>Skilled sales people are always in demand. When making financial decisions, many people still like to talk to a human being and shake someone’s hand. That can’t be automated. For that same reason, financial advisors and financial services jobs will continue to be secure options.</p>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=.%2Fcareer-trends-the-important-skills-youll-need-for-the-jobs-of-the-next-upcoming-years%2F&amp;linkname=Career%20trends%3A%20The%20important%20skills%20you%E2%80%99ll%20need%20for%20Job" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=.%2Fcareer-trends-the-important-skills-youll-need-for-the-jobs-of-the-next-upcoming-years%2F&amp;linkname=Career%20trends%3A%20The%20important%20skills%20you%E2%80%99ll%20need%20for%20Job" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_email" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/email?linkurl=.%2Fcareer-trends-the-important-skills-youll-need-for-the-jobs-of-the-next-upcoming-years%2F&amp;linkname=Career%20trends%3A%20The%20important%20skills%20you%E2%80%99ll%20need%20for%20Job" title="Email" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=.%2Fcareer-trends-the-important-skills-youll-need-for-the-jobs-of-the-next-upcoming-years%2F&#038;title=Career%20trends%3A%20The%20important%20skills%20you%E2%80%99ll%20need%20for%20Job" data-a2a-url="./../../../career-trends-the-important-skills-youll-need-for-the-jobs-of-the-next-upcoming-years/index.html" data-a2a-title="Career trends: The important skills you’ll need for Job"></a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../career-trends-the-important-skills-youll-need-for-the-jobs-of-the-next-upcoming-years/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
