<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tips For Employer &#8211; LinkHS</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Helping teenagers find jobs since 2021</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 07:35:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>
	<item>
		<title>General Working Rules For An Ideal Employer</title>
		<link>./../../../general-working-rules-for-an-ideal-employer/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../general-working-rules-for-an-ideal-employer/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bimal Dhanu]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 07:35:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips For Employer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://demo.nokriwp.com/?p=86</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[General work rules often considered Choosing a simple set of work regulations made up of a few generally accepted as [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4><strong>General work rules often considered</strong></h4>
<p>Choosing a simple set of work regulations made up of a few generally accepted as well as prohibited conducts is much advised. In place of a lengthy set of regulations, small businesses are advised to go for a simple list of regulations and guidelines for making it clear to the workers what sort of behaviour was expected from their part.</p>
<h4><strong>Here is a set of simple set of general workplace rules</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li>Safety rules to be observed</li>
<li>Tardiness policy explaining the way to report the number of sick days allowable and personal off days erased</li>
<li>Time of work to be recorded (Using a time sheet or clock)</li>
<li>Rules of the lunch period and other breaks</li>
<li>Policy for overtime</li>
<li>Rules regarding personal appearance including dress code</li>
<li>Employer’s property damage rules</li>
<li>Rules on maintaining sensitive information of the employers as well as the customers</li>
</ul>
<p>To quote from Michelle Obama</p>
<blockquote><p>We learned about honesty and integrity &#8211; that the truth matters&#8230; that you don&#8217;t take shortcuts or play by your own set of rules&#8230; and success doesn&#8217;t count unless you earn it fair and square.</p></blockquote>
<h4><strong>As a defence against wrongful discharge claims</strong></h4>
<p>Even for at-will employers that have greater freedom for allowing workers to leave for avoiding legal hassles involved with termination procedures, the reasoning of any such action should be wanted to be sound as well as defensible. One way to ensure this is by having a number of basic and vividly stated employees’ rules well communicated to the workers. By this, any worker breaking a work rule ends up doing so with the knowledge that his conduct is not acceptable and such conduct might end up in inviting termination.</p>
<h4><strong>Safeguard step from discrimination claims</strong></h4>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignright wp-image-89 size-medium" src="https://elementor.nokriwp.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/pexels-photo-70292-1-288x300.jpeg" alt="" width="288" height="300" /></p>
<p>If a worker is fired or disciplined on grounds of breaking general employee regulations, even while another one is spared despite facing similar charges, the business could be violating regulations based on anti-discrimination. Maintaining a clear list of work rules makes sure that all workers understand the acceptable and unacceptable behaviour. If the rule set in this regard is ambiguous carrying out of such a rule could invite challenge as discriminatory or arbitrary which is important.even while another one is spared despite facing similar charges</p>
<h4><strong>Points to ponder while choosing work rules</strong></h4>
<h5>Quality of work can be improved by work rules when</h5>
<ul>
<li>An atmosphere is created where workers are treated with respect and dignity</li>
<li>Employees are helped to ensure their own conduct in a safe as well as professional manner</li>
<li>Open communication between the business and its employees are encouraged</li>
<li>All workers are ensured fair treatment and a common set of regulation to follow</li>
</ul>
<h4><strong>Work rules to selected reasonably and appropriately</strong></h4>
<p>Finally, while the conduct of all employees is expected to be governed by certain rules based on work, the specific rules chosen are expected to be reasonable and appropriate for the work being done by the employees in question alongside the working conditions where they are placed in.</p>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=.%2Fgeneral-working-rules-for-an-ideal-employer%2F&amp;linkname=General%20Working%20Rules%20For%20An%20Ideal%20Employer" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=.%2Fgeneral-working-rules-for-an-ideal-employer%2F&amp;linkname=General%20Working%20Rules%20For%20An%20Ideal%20Employer" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_email" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/email?linkurl=.%2Fgeneral-working-rules-for-an-ideal-employer%2F&amp;linkname=General%20Working%20Rules%20For%20An%20Ideal%20Employer" title="Email" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=.%2Fgeneral-working-rules-for-an-ideal-employer%2F&#038;title=General%20Working%20Rules%20For%20An%20Ideal%20Employer" data-a2a-url="./../../../general-working-rules-for-an-ideal-employer/index.html" data-a2a-title="General Working Rules For An Ideal Employer"></a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../general-working-rules-for-an-ideal-employer/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
